# **DILLON ROSE**

#### **Full Stack Engineer**

\$\( \( \text{(954) 579-2558} \) @ DR@dillonmrose.com
\$\( \text{0 linkedin.com/in/dillonmrose} \) \$\( \text{V Seattle} \)

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Full Stack Engineer with a decade of experience building Alpowered user experiences. I've played a key role in developing three projects from the ground up, two of which I led as a tech lead, with both scaling to over 1M MAU. I have a solid grasp of the processes and structures required to deliver new features, while also ensuring live site reliability and maintaining code health. My experience building Microsoft Copilot makes me uniquely qualified to contribute to ChatGPT for Work.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

React	Next.js	Python
C#	VSCode	Al Fluent

#### SOFT SKILLS

Technical documentation

**Cross-Functional Collaboration** 

**Cross-Org Communication** 

Security Best Practices

Data Governance

# INTERESTS



Rock climbing



Construction

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Principal Software Engineer

#### Microsoft Copilot

**=** 01/2023 - Present

- Shipped Microsoft Copilot on Teams, Outlook, Windows, Bing, Office.com and the standalone site serving ~7M DAU
- Designed full stack solution for Turn 0 Prompt Suggestions which initiate ~3% of sessions
- Designed and developed Teaching Moments feature serving 10+ tutorials to onboard users and upsell the paid feature set
- Reduced time to ship to production from 2 weeks to 3 days by re-architecting the deployment strategy

### Senior Software Engineer

#### Cortana

**=** 01/2017 - 01/2023

- Developed email search and composition capabilities for the initial launch of Cortana Invoke
- Incubated and scaled 'Play My Emails' feature to over 1M MAU
- Improved user experience by designing custom audio streaming protocol for email readouts
- Participated on user panels to evaluate existing and experimental features

## Software Engineer II

#### Microsoft Maps

**=** 01/2016 - 01/2017

- Enhanced user experience by optimizing map icons displayed across multiple zoom levels on Bing Maps
- Developed Offline Search capabilities in the Windows Map app by rearchitecting Bing's online search stack
- Defined strategy for selecting which locations and businesses would be downloaded for offline search

# Software Engineer

### Bing

**=** 06/2014 - 01/2016

- Enhanced user satisfaction by optimizing a classifier and a ranker in Bing Local Search stack
- Reduced latency and business costs by developing rule-based classifier to serve head queries

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**



#### Copilot for All

Significantly increased the number of Copilot users by adding support for unlicensed business users and licensed consumer users. We are predicting 80M new licenses to come this effort representing \$28B/year.



#### **Knowledge Sharing Series**

Led organization-wide learning series. Starting from the beginning of the development of Copilot to now, there have been 55 talks covering React basics, zustand, authentication, testability, performance, transformers, etc. I personally presented on VectorDBs, LangChain, scorecards and "The Effective Engineer" by Edmond Lau.

#### **EDUCATION**

# B.S. in Computer Science and Mathematical Sciences

GPA **3.93** / **4.0**